Guide to the Birge M. Clark Architectural Drawings SC0838
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Architectural Drawings
  - Black, Howard, 389 (Box Sc4)
    8 plans for moutain residence, 1935
    Address: Alpine Road
    City: Santa Clara County
  - Clark, Esther and David B.
    Map of Esther Clark and David B. Clark property along Los Trancos Creek - 2 items
  - Pallansch, Paul E.
    1 plan for alterations to residence, 1934; INCORRECTLY LABELED AS JOB #387
    Address: 1226 Warren St.
  - Hamilton, Harold L., 381
    11 plans, 1934
  - Marx, Guido V.D., 1934-05-22
    alteration to dining room - 1 plan, n.d.
  - Santa Clara County Council, Boy Scouts of America, 395 (Box Sc4)
    Swimming pool at camp near Davenport, CA - 2 plans, 1935
    City: Davenport, CA
  - Abrahamson, Mrs. Jack, 396 (Box Sc4)
    1 plan, alterations and additions to cottage, 1935
  - Quigley, C. E., 399 (Box Sc4)
    4 plans, 1935
    Address: Magdalena near Fremont
  - Whisler, George H., 417 (Box Sc11)
    3 plans, 1936
    Address: 1975 Webster St.
  - City of Palo Alto; Palo Alto Library Addition, 1922-05-31; 149 (Box Sc1)
    2 blueprints, revised heating layout, n.d.; Specifications for the Revised Heating in Box B1
  - Jones, Elliot, 434 (Box Sc5)
    Address: Santa Cruz Ave.
  - Atkinson, Judge J. M., 431 (Box Sc5)
    Address: Church St.
  - Clark, Donald E., 433 (Box Sc5)
    Address: Norma Drive (lot 642) - Talmadge Park
    City: San Diego, CA
  - Norris, Judge Allen G., 426 (Box Sc5)
    Address: 140 Thornton Avenue
  - McHenry, Reynolds, 447 (Box Sc5)
    7 plans, 1937
  - Steinhart, Jesse H., 446 (Box Sc5)
    Pool and bathhouse - 2 plans, 1937
    Address: El Monte
  - Fontana (Box Sd10)
    Fontana sketch 2 and 3: 5 plans, n.d. [bird’s eye renderings of building layouts for some sort of industrial plant - no info on drawings]
  - Cooley, E. C., 491 (Box Sc8)
    3 plans, 1939
  - Givan, C. V., 461 (Box Sc8)
    Roll 1 - 7 plans, 1937 (pencil on paper); Roll 2 - 7 plans, copies, 1937
    Address: Alameda, College Park
    City: Davis, CA
  - Gygax, Paul, 464 (Box Sc8)
    Address: Sycamore St. & Thornton Ave.
  - Schink, Mrs. C. E., 465 (Box Sc8)
    2 plans, 1937
    City: San Pedro, CA
  - Chamberlain, William, 466 (Box Sc8)
    1 plans, 1937
    City: Saratoga, CA
  - Rich, W. H., 456 (Box Sc8)
  - Peck, Robert, 457 (Box Sc8)
    3 plans, 1937
    Address: Pettis Ave. & Snow St.
  - Hughes, Mrs. Thomas, 458 (Box Sc8)
    Alterations to gardener’s cottage - 1 plan, 1937
  - Winterburn, J. C., 468 (Box Sc8)
    Address: Valparaiso Avenue
  - Hardy, Dr. Sumner, 469 (Box Sc8)
    Alterations to dummer house - 2 plans, 1938
    Address: Shine Road
  - Michaels, Alan J., 470 (Box Sc8)
    10 plans, 1938
    Address: Isabella & Britton
  - Murray, Jay C., 471 (Box Sc11)
    5 plans, 1938; 1 topo map of site by F. A. Herrmann, 1938
    Address: Piedmont Road
  - Decoto Grammar School, 472 (Box Sc8)
    Reconstruction 5 plans, 1938
  - Diamond Horse Training Corrals, 544 (Box Sc2)
    1 plan, undated
  - Stanford Medical School. Research Lab donated by Lucie Stern, 490
    ca. 18 plans, 1939
    Address: Clay near Webster
    City: San Francisco
  - Griffin, Willard C., 476 (Box Sc8)
    3 plans for swimming pool & dressing rooms, 1938
    Address: El Monte Rd.
  - Allied Arts Guild, residence for, 477 (Box Sc8)
    Address: Arbor Place (lot #6)
  - Mountain View Union High School, 475 (Box Sc8)
    Addition to, 12 plans, 1938
  - Mountain View Union High School, 485 (Box Sc8)
    Alterations to, Nov. 1938, 1 plan; ROLLED WITH FILE 475
  - Warriner, Mrs. Harwood, 482 (Box Sc8)
    8 plans, 1938
    Address: El Camino Grande East
    City: near Los Gatos, CA
  - Mountain View Union High School, 520 (Box Sb9)
    Addition to gymnasium building, 6 plans, 1940
  - Clark, David B., 498 (Box Sc11)
    Address: Fremont Rd. near Atascadero
  - Butler, Alice, 495 (Box Sc8)
    5 plans, May 1939; 6 plans June 1939
    Address: Tuskaloosa Ave. at Selby Lane
  - Golden Gate Internatl Exposition; Golden Gate Internatl Exposition, 497
    Proposed Philippines Exposition Building at the Golden Gate International Exposition for 1939 - 2 original pencil on paper and 16 blueprints
  - Mountain View Union High School, 501 (Box Sb9)
    Bleachers, 1 plan, 1939
  - Cahn, R. C., 504 (Box Sb9)
    Alterations and additions to residence, 2 plans, 1939
    Address: Edgewood Drive
  - LeRoy, Rene, 500 (Box Sb9)
    Stable, 1 plan, 1939
    Address: Glenwood Ave.
  - LeRoy, Rene, 555 (Box Sb9)
    Alterations to service porch, March 1941 (presumed to be Atherton residence); ROLLED WITH FILE # 500
    Address: [Glenwood Ave.]
    City: [Atherton, CA]
  - LeRoy, Rene, 555 (Box Sc2)
    Proposed ranch house, 3 plans, Sept. 1941
    City: near Guadalupe (S. Barbara County)
  - Borley, Dr.; Borley, Dr., 511 (Box Sb9)
    Proposed office and residence, 3 plans, 1939; [no address on plans; file number taken from original tube]
  - Burr, Charles J., 514 (Box Sb9)
    4 plans, 1940; bedroom addition, 1 plan, 1945
    Address: Nash Ave. near Santa Margerita Ave. (Nash tract)
    City: San Mateo County
  - Centerville Elementary School, 517 (Box Sb9)
    11 plans, 1940
  - Stevens, Howard, 526 (Box Sb9)
    Address: Portola & Dixon Avenues
  - Mannon, Mrs. F. B., 529 (Box Sb9)
    Music studio, 5 plans, 1940
    Address: Isabella Avenue
  - Norris, C. G., 534 (Box Sb9)
    Fry cottage and Maid’s cottage additions - 1 plan, 1940
  - Armes, George D., 536 (Box Sb9)
    Outdoor dining room - 2 plans, n.d.
  - Permanente Lab ( - this name only on tube), 538 (Box Sb9)
    Magnesium Plant - perspective, 1 drawing, n.d.
    City: Tahoe, CA
  - Ulmer, Maurice C., 541 (Box Sb9)
    Address: Vista Lane
    City: Burlingame, CA
  - Salabert, Jacques, 541 (Box Sb9)
    Store and garage building - 4 plans, 1945
    Address: High Street near Channing
  - Davies, A. L., 550 (Box Sc2)
    Additions to residence - 1 plan, 1941
  - Prior, Mr. & Mrs. Leland S., 307 (Box Sc7)
    7 drawings, May 26, 1928
    Address: Middlefield
  - Davies Auto Company, 551 (Box Sc2)
    5 drawings for garage and auto sales building, Aug. 5, 1941
    Address: 1101 El Camino Real
  - Ramsay, Mrs. Elizabeth W., 554 (Box Sc2)
    7 drawings, Aug. 30, 1941
    Address: Polhemus Ave & Alademeda de las Pulgas
  - Patten, Mrs. Lenore Grey, 693 (Box Sc11)
    Addition to residence, 1 drawing, 4/28/49; FILED WITH NO. 557
  - Perishables Shipping Equipment Co., 562 (Box Sc2)
    Refrigerated Lift Container, 10 drawings, 1942
  - Registrar’s Office; Stanford University. Registrar’s Office, 578 (Box Sc2)
    Alterations to Registrar’s Office, 3 drawings, 8/18/42
  - Henry J. Kaiser Co., 580 (Box Sc2)
    Scale house, 1 drawing, 8/12/42; [File number taken from original tube - not on the item]
    City: Radum, CA
  - Henry J. Kaiser Co., 581 (Box Sc2)
    Locker, Lavatory, & Time building, 10/12/42; [ROLLED WITH #580]
  - City of San Carlos Fire Dept., 590 (Box Sc2)
    San Carlos Fire House, 9 drawings, 5/27/40
    Address: Laurel Street
    City: San Carlos, CA
  - U. S. Navy / Carl N. Swenson Company, 601 (Box Sc2)
    Submarine Repair Facilities. Additions to office building, 4 drawings, no date [Clark name is not on these items, they may product of Swenson Company]
    Address: 16th Street Pier
  - Sutter Packing Company, 602 (Box Sc2)
    Platform covering warehouse building, 1 drawing, 10/5/44
  - I. Ruderman, 606 (Box Sc2)
    Shed roof for dehydrator, 1 drawing, 5/1/45
    Address: Central Avenue
  - Carr, Mr. & Mrs. William H., 608 (Box Sc2)
    4 drawings, 1945; [Drawings labeled job no. 608 but tube was labeled 608-A; there is a different building with job no. 608.]
    Address: 1151 University Avenue
  - Hyman, Charles S., 299 (Box Sc7)
    Address: Stockbridge & Amador
  - Roller, D. Rae Te, 430 (Box Sc5)
    2 drawings, 1936; Possibly same house as in #299
  - Fromm, Aug., 300 (Box Sc7)
    Address: Broadway Street
  - Menlo School for Boys, 301 (Box Sc7)
    Swimming pool: 3 drawings, 1928
    Address: El Camino
  - Menlo School for Boys, 302 (Box Sc7)
    Dormitory: 8 drawings, 1928
  - Morrell, George, 308 (Box Sc7)
    7 drawings, 1928; 2 drawings, 1946
    Address: Coleridge & Cowper
  - Smith, N. Browing, 309 (Box Sc7)
    11 drawings, 1928
    Address: [Eleanor Drive ?]
    City: Woodside Heights, CA
  - Lockey, R., 316 (Box Sc9)
    Addition, 1 drawing, 1928
    Address: 1404 Bryant Street
  - Currence, H. D., 317 (Box Sc9)
    Address: Marlborough Rd.
  - Mikel, Rossiter L., 323 (Box Sc9)
    13 drawings, 1929
    Address: Lot 6 Hampton Court
    City: Piedmont, CA
  - Newmark, Henry M., 325 (Box Sc9)
    10 drawings, no date [ca. 1929]; 1 drawing 1936
    Address: Saratoga-Los Gatos Highway
    City: Saratoga ??
  - Newmark, Henry M., 341
    servant’s house, 2 drawings, 1929
  - Gallagher, 328 (Box Sc9)
    Addition to residence, 7+ drawings, ca. 1929
    Address: Kings Mountain Road
  - Ravenswood Public School, 312 (Box Sc7)
    New stage and manual training shop, 4 drawings, 1928
  - Lyon, Burt W., 327 (Box Sc9)
    10 drawings, 1929
    Address: Glen Una Drive
  - Currier, Fred. J., 331 (Box Sc9)
    Address: Saratoga Avenue
  - Ingold, Ernest, 335 (Box Sc9)
    11 drawings, 1929
  - Aust Realty Company, 334 (Box Sc9)
    1 drawing, 1926
  - Whiting, Mr. and Mrs. H.S, 1929-08-14; 337 (Box Sc9)
    Address: 187 Saratoga
  - Welch, Mr and Mrs. Nell Y, 1929-08-15; 338 (Box Sc9)
    13 Drawings
    Address: Hillsborough Park #2
  - Michaels, Mr. and Mrs. C. F., 1930-03-08; 346 (Box Sc9)
  - El Camino Dormitory Building; Menlo School and Junior College, 1931-03-02; 352 (Box Sc9)
    17 drawings. Includes drawings of later addition
  - Duncan, Mrs. Edith L, 1935-07-11; 343 (Box Sc9)
    10 Drawings
    Address: 611 Coronado
  - Baumgartner, Mr and Mrs John Jay, 1930-02-10; 344 (Box Sc9)
    Address: Spencer Lane
  - Wilbur, Dr. & Mrs. Blake C., 351 (Box Sc9)
    Proposed cabin, 1 drawing (by David B. Clark), undated
  - Johnson, Dr. and Mrs. Richard, 5808
    1 drawing (kitchen remodel), n.d.
    Address: 474 Churchill
    Architect: Clark, Stromquist, David F. Potter, Joseph Ehrlich
  - Braden, Mrs. Angela C., 1924-05-19; 205 (Box Sc10)
    Address: corner of Amelia ave. and MacBain ave.
  - Collier, J.B, 1924-06-23; 208 (Box Sc10)
    Address: Portola Woods
  - Boyn Braden Theatre Building, 1924-12-12; 222 (Box Sc10)
    Address: state highway
    City: Menlo Park
  - Stafford, Gro. E, 1925-01; 226 (Box Sc10)
    Address: Edgewood Rd
    City: Redwood City
  - Bank Building for the Menlo Park branch of the Bank of Palo Alto, 1925-04-02; 231 (Box Sc10)
    15 drawings
    Address: El Camino and Santa Cruz ave.
  - Palo Alto Improvement Company, 1925-05-12; 234 (Box Sc10)
    Address: State Highway
  - Kirk, Dr. Josiah H., 1928-10-05; 318 (Box Sc9)
    3 drawings, addition to garage
  - Roberts, Roger M., 210
    1 drawing - revision of bedroom, July 16, 1924
  - Mrs. Lucie Stern, 1929-11-18 (Box Sd10)
    Entrance steps for Mrs. Stern, 3 drawings
  - Boy Scouts, 351 (Box Sc9)
    1 drawing for Boy Scout Trading Post, Swanton, CA, May 1931.; 3 drawings for Boy Scout Cabin, Palo Alto, Oct. 31, 1930 and Dec. 1930
  - Ingold, Ernest, 335
    1 drawing, first and second floor plans, on heavy paper with colored pencil landscaping. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects
  - Mikel, Rossiter L., 323
    Address: Hampton Court
  - El Camino Dormitory Building; Menlo School and Junior College, 352
    1 drawing, on heavy paper with colored pencil landscaping. Paper stamped with seal of the American Institute of Architects
  - Proposed U.S. Post Office
    Elevation, pencil and watercolor, mounted on board, no date
    Address: [Hamilton Ave. and Ramona St.]
  - Stanford Campus Elementary School; Stanford Campus Elementary School, 1950-08-17; 709 (Box Sd10)
    8 Sheets - Plans, Elevations, Section, Door and Window Details, Structural, Plumbing, Electrical & Heating plans.
    Address: Lasuen & Santa Ynez Avenue
    Architect: Clark, Birge M., Walter L. Huber & Edward M.Knapik
  - Trace Elementary School, 675 (Box Sc3)
    12 Sheets - Plans, elevations, Sections, Framing Plans, Door & Window Details, Structural Details, Plumbing, heating and Electrical Plans
    Address: Dana Street
  - Brewer, D.W., 1926-04; 264 (Box Sd9)
    Address: Edgewood Park
  - Fowle, Mr & Mrs. A. E., 1926-03-30; 260 (Box Sd9)
    7 sheets + 1 survey sheet
  - Goodenough, Wells. P., 1926-04-19; 261 (Box Sd9)
    Address: Edge Wood Park
  - Borley, Dr. W. E., 1926-04-06; 262 (Box Sd9)
  - White, Mr. C. A., 1926-06-17; 270 (Box Sd9)
    Address: San Antonio
  - Beene, Mr & Mrs, 1953-03; 757 (Box Sd10)
    Address: 1457 Hamilton Avenue
  - Saier, M., 1948-05; 671 (Box Sc3)
    6 Sheets + 1 Site Plan
    Address: Santa Maria
    City: Del Mar
  - Maynard, Dr. & Mrs, 1948-02; 667 (Box Sc3)
    Address: Saratoga Road
    City: Los Gatos
  - Palo Alto Clinic, 1947-1952; 722 (Box Sd10)
    total 9 sheets: 2 sheets 1947 alterations; 1 sheet 1948 alterations; 3 sheets of March 1951 alterations; 1 sheet June 1951 Woodside office; 2 sheets 1952 alterations
    Address: Corner of Bryant & Homer
  - Lytton Avenue school, 1950-05; 708 (Box Sd10)
    9 Sheets
    Address: Lytton Avenue
  - Steele, Ralph, 1948-06; 676 (Box Sc3)
    Address: La Cuesta Road
  - Nash Garage, 1953-02; 755 (Box Sd10)
    Address: High Street at Channing Avenue
  - Browne, 1953-07; 753
    9 sheets + 3 sheets
    Address: Site No. 80, Goya Road
  - May, Alfred; May's Apartments, 1967-08; 743 (Box Sd10)
    4 sheets + 1 sheet
    Address: 727, 735, 741 Middlefield Road
  - McCollister, Paul, 1951-01; 715 (Box Sd10)
    8 Sheets + 1 Sheet
    Address: 66 Acacia Drive, Lindenwood,
  - Peninsular Chevrolet, 1952-08; 752 (Box Sd10)
    2 sheets + 2 sheets (file number 804, dated May 1955)
    Address: High Street at Forest Avenue
  - Haynes, Mr. Gilman, 1949-08; 696 (Box Sc3)
    Address: Wildcrest Drive
  - Luck, Charles, 1949-08; 697 (Box Sc3)
    Address: Aloha Avenue & Komina Avenue
  - City of Palo Alto Fire Department, 1950-03; 704 (Box Sd10)
    Address: Bryant Street
  - Houser, Mrs. Maxwell, 1921-12; 147 (Box Sc1)
    Address: Portola Woods Near Woodside
    City: San Mateo County, CA
  - Frier, W. L., 1922-04; 146 (Box Sc1)
  - Wild, Mr. Morris, 1922-04; 154 (Box Sc1)
    6 Sheets + 1 Sheet
    Address: 1620 Webster Street
  - Humbleton, Mrs Frances, 1922-06; 158 (Box Sc1)
  - Wilkins, Miss Alice N., 1922-08; 160 (Box Sd8)
  - Wight, W. F., 1922-07; 159 (Box Sc1)
    5 Sheets + 3 sheets
    Address: Baron Sub Division
  - Lowenstein, Mrs Charlie May, 1922-08; 161 (Box Sd8)
    Address: O'Connor Street
    City: Runnymede
  - Wright, Charles F., 1922-07-08; 173 (Box Sd8)
    Address: lots 3,4 &5 Block 32 Waverly Street
  - Peet, Mrs. Harriet, 1923-01-29; 174 (Box Sd8)
    Address: Coleridge & Cowper Street
  - sketches of a trellis or pergola (Box Sd10)
    Untitled sketches mostly of a trellis or pergola
  - Van. Hausven, Mr. Karel H., 1921-11-21; 44 (Box Sc1)
    Address: Almedral Avenue, Selby Tract
  - Kenyon, Glenn C., 1921-09-20; 43 (Box Sc1)
    Address: Webster Street
    City: Embarcadero, Palo Alto, CA
  - Delta Upsilon House (Box Sd10)
    3 Sheets ( drawings contain approval signatures by Charles Hodges & Branner who was a trustee for the Delta Upsilon House).
  - Congelton, E. D. (Box Sd10)
    only 1 of 3 Sheets available, no date
    Address: Lot no 15, Block no 19
    City: South Palo Alto, CA
  - Moan, A. J., 1923-02; 176 (Box Sd8)
    Address: Easton Drive, Lot 12, Block 57, Subdivision #6
    City: Burlingame, California
  - Champlin, W. K., 1923-06; 184 (Box Sd8)
    9 Sheets + 2 Sheets
    Address: Moody Road,
    City: Los Altos, CAlifornia
  - [proposed bungalow complex], unknown (Box Sd10)
    5 plans for bungalow complex - 1 large plan for whole design (7 houses) and 4 smaller plans for individual units
  - The Warren Furniture Co., 1923-11; 193 (Box Sd8)
    Address: Emerson, Between Hamilton & Forest Avenue
  - Langnecker, Dr. Harry L., 1923-10; 190 (Box Sd8)
    Address: Corner of Lowell & Webster
  - Williams, Mrs. Anne D., 1923-10; 192 (Box Sd8)
    Address: Lincoln Avenue
  - Laumeister, Mrs Mabel S., 1921-10; 42 (Box Sc1)
    Address: Webster & Coleridge Street
  - McDowell, Mr. John E., 1920-04-12; 30 (Box Sc1)
    Address: Lot 15 Block 22
  - Tnote, Mrs L.A., 33 (Box Sc1)
    11 Sheets
  - Delta Tau Delta Chapter house, 24 (Box Sc1)
    Address: Lot no 11 San Juan Extension
  - McFarland, Dr. F. M., 26 (Box Sc1)
  - Clark, A.B., 1939-11 (Box Sd10)
    Address: on Via Olivera 2 blocks west of Alto Camino
    City: Palm Springs
  - Clark, A. B., 1909; 27 (Box Sc1)
    Proposed house...Lot. No. 7 of the Reservoir addition: 2 sheets (vellum)1909 + 2 Sheets (paper) undated. [File no. on original tube but not on drawings.]
    Address: 767 Santa Ynez ["San Ynez" on drawings]
  - Goodenough, W. P., 1924-03-17; 200 (Box Sc10)
    Address: Lowell & Webster
  - Merner Lumber Co., 1924-05-26; 196 (Box Sd8)
    4 Sheets (196 b) + 9 Sheet of sketches + 6 sheets (196 a) + 1 sheet
    Address: Merner Tract
  - Stern, Mrs. Louis, 1932-02-08; 360 (Box Sc4)
    Two residences for Mrs. Louis Stern, 10 drawings on tissue and 2 reproductions, Jan. 27, 1932
  - Hoover, Herbert, 29 (Box Sc1)
    paper copies of a 3-sheet set [not marked with any file number], Sept. 17, 1919: Ground, first and second floor plans
  - Laumeister, Gustav, 180
    1 roll unprocessed marked "sealed dwgs in poor condition"
  - U. S. Post Office, 364
    2 tubes (blueprints) unprocessed - mechanical, structural
    Address: Hamilton
  - Menlo School, 329
    1 tube unprocessed
  - Cardinal Hotel, 266
  - Washington Union High School
    1 tube unprocessed for file numbers 345 (gym), 391 (earthquake reconstruction), 414 (machine shop), 473 (cafeteria), 480 (unspecified), 483 (garage, warehouse), 532 (lath house)
  - Dnotes, John (plans completed), 1946-01-10; 615 (Box Sc11)
    5 plans, 1946 - blueprints [accn 2006-322 ]; [residence was never built]
  - City of Palo Alto; Palo Alto Police and Fire Station, 1927-04-28; 249 (Box Sc15)
    Blueprints (Steel Construction Company) mostly for cell blocks (doors, partitions, ceilings, bunks window guards, gratings, etc.) June 1927 - BRITTLE, SOME ARE DAMAGED
  - U. S. Post Office, 364 (Box Sb10)
    Roll 1: Blueprints (architectural): first and mezzanine floor plans, approach plan, and exterior details, 1932
    Address: Hamilton Avenue
  - U. S. Post Office, 364 (Box Sb10)
    Roll 2: Blueprints (architectural): basement floor plan, rear elevation, street plot, lighting fixtures, fireproof vault, 1932
  - U. S. Post Office, 364 (Box Sb10)
    Roll 3: Blueprints (architectural): right & left elevation, sections, detail of roof construction, screen line sections & elevation details, details of parcel post window & counter, lock boxes, 1932
  - Marx, G. V. D., undated
    specifications for house [blueprints are in map case Sd10]
  - City of Palo Alto; Palo Alto Library Addition, 1922-05-31; 149
    Specifications for the Revised Heating of the Palo Alto Public Library. The Cnoteington Co. [Blueprints are in Map Case Sc1]
- Additional Architectural Drawings, Accession ARCH-2017-021
  - Five Houses for Mrs. Herber Hoover Front View, M910E (Box 1)
  - Five Houses for Mrs. Herber Hoover Top View, M910b (Box 1)
  - Five Houses for Mrs. Herber Hoover Roof View, M910a (Box 1)
  - Five Houses for Mrs. Herber Hoover Group Elevation, M910d (Box 1)
  - Five Houses for Mrs. Herber Hoover Detailed Elevation, M910c (Box 1)